我们目前正在使用地图
we're currently using a map
代表我们的谈话
to represent our conversation
和地图是一个通用的数据结构
and maps are a generic data structure
我们可以向地图添加任意键和值
we can add arbitrary keys and values to maps
但我们的谈话有一些隐含的限制
but our conversation has some implied constraints
它有一组带有默认值的固定字段
it has a fixed set of fields with default values
因为它是我们应用程序的中心数据结构
and since it's the central data structure of our app
它流经整个管道
it flows through the entire pipeline
我们想给它更多的结构
we'd like to give it a bit more structure
这正是结构给我们的
and that's exactly what a structure gives us
现在一个结构需要自己生活
now a structure needs to live in its own
模块，我们也会把它放在它自己的文件中
module and we'll put it in its own file too
在 lib 调查下将创建一个新文件
under lib survey will create a new file
我们称之为骗局
and we'll call it con
前任
ex
然后在其中我们将定义我们的 con 模块
and then inside of that we'll define our co n module
服务网络
service nv
然后在我们使用的那个模块中定义一个结构
then to define a structure within that module we use
定义结构
def structure
我们传递给它一个关键字列表，它看起来像这样
and we pass it a keyword list it looks like this
方括号
square brackets
然后在里面
and then inside of there
我们列出这个结构的字段
we list the fields of this structure
所以其中之一是方法
so one of them is method
那是字段的名称
that's the name of the field
然后我们可以给它默认值
and then we can give it default values
这个只是一个空字符串
this one's just going to be an empty string
与路径相同
same way with path
响应体也是空的
response body is also empty
然后我们有一个状态字段
and then we have a status field
我们将默认为 nil
and we'll default that to nil
关键字列表
keyword lister
通常用于将选项传递给函数
commonly used to pass options to a function
或者在这种情况下是一个长生不老药宏
or in this case an elixir macro
因为关键字列表是最后一个
since the keyword list is the last
唯一的论点
and only argument
我们实际上可以删除方括号
we can actually remove the square brackets
那么这个结构的名称是什么
so what's the name of this structure
好吧，它与模块 servey 的名称相同
well it's the same as the name of the module servey
co 和 v 这就是为什么结构必须存在于模块中的原因
co and v that's why a structure must live in a module
你不能定义
and you can't define
不止一次被击中
more than one struck
每个模块，所以让我们保存它
per module so let's save that
离开，我们将启动一个 ix 会话
away and we'll fire up an ix session
只是为了感受
just to get a feel
关于 s 的工作原理
for how the s works
我在顶级调查目录中
I'm inside of the top level survey directory
我将使用修复
and I'm going to use fix
s mix 以便我们将其作为混合应用程序运行
s mix so that we're running this as a mix application
你注意到它解释为
and you notice it interpreted that
模块之外的代码
code that was outside of the module
所以
so
我只是要把它清理干净然后回到顶部
I'm just going to clean this up and go back to the top
所以你可能还记得我们是如何创建地图的
so you probably remember how we create a map
我们只使用百分比，然后像这样的花括号
we just use per cent and then curly braces like that
同样，我们可以创建一个结构
well similarly we can create a structure
通过使用 % 花括号
by using % curly braces
但
but
在他们两个之间，我们把被击中的名字
between the two of them we put the name of the struck
所以这是服务端
so it's servey co n
我们注意到结果是严格的
and we notice the result is a strict
它有这些
it's got these
使用默认值固定其中的字段
fixed fields inside of it with their default values
现在我们也可以创建结构和供应
now we can also create the structure and supply
覆盖这些默认值的值
values to override those defaults
所以如果我们想覆盖方法
so if we wanted to override method
我们只会说方法
we would just say method
会得到
would be get
例如，路径可能是斜线熊
and maybe the path would be slash bears for example
你注意到方法现在是 get
and you notice the method is now get
路径是熊
and the path is bears
然后我们有默认值
and then we have the default values
对于其余字段
for the remaining fields
现在不像地图，我们不能用它来创建结构
now unlike a map we can't create a structure with
不在关键字列表中的字段，例如
a field that's not in the keyword list like
名字是迈克
name is mike
现在你可能会
now you'd probably
永远不要像这样添加虚假字段
never just add a spurious field like this
但如果你像我一样
but if you're like me
那么您可能会错过字段类型
then you're likely to miss type of field
比如你可能忘记了 o 和方法
like maybe you forget the o and method
是的，这里的好处是
yeah what's nice here is
在编译时检查约束
the constraint is checked at compile time
所以拼写错误的字段名称不会漏掉
so misspelled field names won't slip through
例如，现在让我们摆脱所有这些红色
for example now let's get rid of all this red
我们将回到版本
and we'll just go back to the version
拼写正确
that had this spelled right
我们可以访问结构的字段
and we can access fields of the structure
就像访问地图一样
just like accessing a map
使用点符号
using dot notation
所以如果我们想看看方法
so if we want to look at the method
或者我们想看看路径
or we want to look at the path
嗯，这是熟悉的点符号
well it's the familiar dot notation
我们习惯了地图
we're used to with a map
但与地图不同，方括号语法不起作用
but unlike maps the square bracket syntax won't work
所以我们尝试这样做
so we try to do this
好吧，我们收到一条错误消息
well we get an error message
所以你可以说结构具有更严格的访问权限
so you can say that structures have stricter access
因为他们不允许动态访问
since they don't allow dynamic access
像地图一样使用方括号
using square brackets like maps do
例如，我们仍然在 ix 中加载我们的地图
for example we still have our map loaded up in ix here
如果我想尝试访问
and if I would try to access
该地图的年龄键
the age key of that map
好吧，它只是返回 nil
well it just returns nil
但是如果我们尝试做同样的事情
but if we try to do the same
与我们的合作和 v 发生的事情
thing with our co and v struck
好吧，我们得到了一个实际的错误，而不是返回 nil
well we get an actual error rather than returning nil
所以再次受到打击，我们得到编译时检查
so again with a struck we get compile time checking
这通常可以节省你的培根
which often saves your bacon
现在更新结构类似于更新地图
now updating a structure is similar to updating a map
例如
for example
假设我们想将状态码更新为 200
let's say we wanted to update the status code to 200
我们将使用这种熟悉的语法，我们说 co 和 v
we'll use this familiar syntax we say co and v
一个竖线，然后是 200 的状态
a vertical bar and then status of 200
然后我们看到状态已经更新
then we see the status has been updated
那么我们也可以模式匹配struts
it follows then that we can also pattern match struts
所以我让我的 co 和 v 开始了
so I have my co and v struck on the
右侧
right hand side
我想在左边写一个图案
and I want to write a pattern on the left hand
与之匹配的一面
side that matches it
好吧，这将是服务
well it would be servey
co 和 v 如果我只是使用方法作为 get
co and v and if I just use method as get
看起来像那样
looks like that
好吧，那会匹配，因为这是一个打击
well that'll match because this is a co n struck
它肯定有一个
and it certainly has a
值为 get 的字段方法
field method with a value of get
我们不在乎里面还有什么
and we don't care what else is in there
因为记得在左边
because remember on the left hand side
我们不必提供所有字段来匹配
we don't have to give all the fields to get a match
以同样的方式，我们可以将其与状态相匹配
in the same way we could match it against a status
例如 200
of 200 for example
毫不奇怪
and no surprise
我们还可以在模式匹配中提取值
we can also extract values in the pattern match
正如我们已经了解到的
as we've already learned
是的，我将在那里使用变量方法
yeah I'll just use the variable method right there
那是一场比赛
and that's a match
如果我们很好地查看方法，它就会绑定到字符串
and if we look at method well it's bound to the string
get so 使用结构感觉很像使用地图
get so using a structure feels a lot like using a map
实际上是一个严格的例子
and in fact a strict instance
只是一种特殊的地图
is just a special kind of map
具有一组厚实的键和默认值
with a thick set of keys and default values
我们可以测试一下里面有一个函数
and we can kind of test that there's a function in
灵药叫做是图
elixir called is map
如果我们通过 co 和 v 它肯定会返回
if we pass at co and v it returns sure enough
所以它遵循
so it follows
那么如果我们回到这里的表格
then if we were to go back to this form here
我们在右边被击中的地方
where we've got a struck on the right
但是我们在左边删除它
but then we remove this on the left
所以这只是一张普通的旧地图
so that this is just a plain old map
好吧，那会匹配，因为我们知道一个结构
well that'll match because we know that a structure
是地图，这是左侧的地图
is a map and this is a map on the left hand side
它有一个方法键和一个 get 值
it has a key of method and a value of get
这个结构肯定有
which this structure certainly has
所以这是一场比赛
and so that's a match
那么反过来呢
so what about the converse
如果我们在左侧有这个严格的模式
if we have this strict pattern on the left hand side
然后在右手边
and then over here on the right hand side
如果我们给它一张普通的旧地图
if we just give it a plain old map
有关键方法的
that has the key method
和价值得到
and the value get
那不匹配，因为地图
well that doesn't match because a map
不是结构
isn't a structure
所以这里有什么大不了的
so what's the big deal here
地图是我们真正关心的结构
maps are structures do we really care
我们确实这样做了，因为通过对结构进行模式匹配
indeed we do because by pattern matching on a structure
我们可以肯定
we can be sure
我们一直在使用预期的地图类型
we're always working with the expected type of map
不只是任何旧地图
not just any old map
这使我们的应用程序代码更加健壮
which makes our application code more robust
所以回到我们的应用程序
so back in our app
让我们先改变
let's first change
地图是如何在我们的解析器中初始化的
how the map is initialized in our parser
是的 现在
yeah right now
我们只是将它初始化为一个普通的老长生不老药地图
we're just initializing it as a plain old elixir map
但我们希望它是一个印章和vs
but we want it to be a seal and v s
我们只是要把它移下来
we're just going to move that down
然后因为我们提供了
and then because we provided
这些的默认值
default values for these
我们定义结构时的两个字段
two fields when we define the structure
好吧，我们不需要在这里这样做
well we don't need to do this here
所以基本上我们要做的就是
so basically what we're going to do is just
覆盖方法路径
override the method path
方法路径变量中的任何内容
with whatever's in the method path variables
所以你可能会认为这就像一个类型化的地图
so you might think of this as like a typed map
如果我们把它保存起来
if we save that away
如果我们说重新编译，然后回到 ix
then back over an ix if we say recompile
好
well
你可能会惊讶地发现它仍然有效
you might be surprised to see that that still works
那是因为如果我们看一下 handler
and that's because if we look at handler
以及我们管道中的所有这些功能
and all these functions in our pipeline
拿这张普通的旧地图
that take this plain old map
虽然我们知道
while we know
如果这是右侧的结构
that if this is a structure on the right hand side
它将匹配左侧的地图
it will match a map on the left hand side
返回并解析
back over and parser
我们需要在其他地方引用这个结构
we'll need to refer to this structure in other places
这很乏味
and it's tedious
打字调查
to type survey
每次都骗
con every time
所以我们可以为这个名字设置一个别名
so instead we can set up an alias for the name
要在模块顶部执行此操作，我们只需使用别名
to do that at the top of the module we just use alias
我们想给服务起别名
we want to alias the serve
v 模块，然后我们可以给它一个名字
v module and then we can give it a name
我们说冒号是一个选项
we say as colon that's an option
我们想把它称为
and we want to refer to it as just
co 和 v 然后在这里我们可以删除这个前缀
co and v and then down here we can remove this prefix
定义别名
defining aliases
这种方式太常见了，有一条捷径
this way is so common that there's a shortcut
如果我们放弃煤炭和期权
if we drop the as coal and option
然后我们得到一个别名，它是名称的最后一部分
then we get an alias that's the last part of the name
那应该可以
and that should work
它确实
and it does
建模的好处之一
one of the benefits of modeling
与地图相比，我们的谈话令人震惊
our conversation is a struck as compared to a map is
我们可以确保管道中的所有功能
we can ensure that all the functions in our pipeline
总是得到预期的类型
always get the expected type
换句话说，我们得到了类型安全
in other words we get type safety
让我们开始我们的插件模块
let's start on our plugins module
首先，我们将别名 service co 和 v
in first we're going to alias service co and v
所以我们不必使用完整的前缀
so we don't have to use the full prefix
然后在这里而不是一张普通的旧地图
and then down here instead of a plain old map
我们希望它是一个合作和 v 打击
we want it to be a co and v struck
我们想在这里做同样的事情
and we want to do the same thing here
请注意，我们并不真正关心这个结构中的内容
notice we don't really care what's in this structure
所以一种方法就是说 c
so a way to do that is just to say c
然后只打开关闭花括号等于
and then just open close curly braces equals
这保证这是一个cnv袭击
and that guarantees that this is a cnv struck
我们不在乎里面有什么
we don't care what's inside of it
但我们确实关心它是那个类型的地图
but we do care that it's that typed map
我们会继续改变这个
we'll go ahead and change this one
我们会在这里做同样的事情
and we'll do the same thing down here
我会接受的
and I'll just take that
我们想做同样的事情
and we want to do this exact same thing
对于日志，现在这些功能将
for log so now these functions will
仅当此参数为 rco 和 b 时才匹配
only match if this argument is rco and b struck
如果是普通的旧地图，它们将不匹配
they won't match if it's a plain old map
把它放在这里也很清楚
and putting this here also makes it clear
就在你看功能头的时候
just when you look at the function head
这些函数只接受 co 和 v 实例
that these functions only accept co and v instances
所以在某种程度上它是一种文档形式
so in a way it's sort of a form of documentation
我们需要在处理程序模块中进行类似的更改
we need to make similar changes in the handler module
再次，我们将从别名开始
again we'll start by aliasing it
然后我们需要在这里更新路由模式
and then we'll need to update the route patterns here
所以这将是 co 和 v
so this is going to be co and v
我只是要复制这个
and I'm just going to copy this
因为我们有一些这样的
because we have a few of these
我们必须把它粘贴到
we've got to paste this into
然后在下面
and then down below
我们也有这种格式的响应
we also have this format response
我们希望这样
and we want that to be
只是任何 co 和 v 袭击
just any co and v struck
如果我们把它保存起来应该仍然有效
if we save that away should still work
现在通常结构是
now it's common for a structure to be the
只有在模块中定义的东西
only thing defined within a module
这就是我们现在所拥有的
and that's what we have right now
但是，当您开始建模实体时
however when you start modeling entities
您的域作为结构
of your domain as structures
就像我们在谈话中所做的那样
as we did with the conversation
您通常最终会定义同步的功能
you often end up defining functions that go hand
与被击中的人牵手
in hand with the struck
定义那些是有意义的
and it makes sense to define those
功能相同
functions in the same
被击中的模块
module as the struck
作为一个简单的例子
as a simple example
如果我们看一下这个格式响应函数
if we look at this format response function
我们在这里解释了这个字符串
we have this string right here being interpreted
它有两个部分
and there's two parts to it
好
well
我们可以通过在 co 中定义一个函数来整理它
we can tidy that up by defining a function in the co
和返回完整状态字符串的 v 模块
and v module that returns the full status string
所以我要把它从这里删掉
so I'm just going to cut this out of here
我们希望它看起来像这样
and we want it to look like this
在 co 和 v 模块上
on the co and v module
我们希望能够调用一个函数
we want to be able to call a function
完整状态，然后我们将传入 co 和 v
full status and then we'll just pass in co and v
那么如果我们继续
then if we go over to that
定义了我们的结构的模块
module that has our structure defined
好吧，我们可以向下添加功能
well we can add functions down
在这里，我们可以在这里定义我们的完整状态函数
here so we can define our full status function here
这只会返回一个
and this is just going to return a
连接的字符串，我只是要粘贴
concatenated string and I'm just going to paste in
我从那里切下来的东西
what I cut from over there
所以它只是插值
so it just interpolates
这两件事的状态和原因
those two things the status and the reason
并返回一个完整的状态字符串
and returns a full status string
现在让它工作
now for this to work
它需要调用这个状态原因函数
it needs to call this status reason function
所以我们也需要将它从处理程序中移过来
so we need to move it over from handler as well
我们就从这里拿过来
we'll just grab it from over here
然后把它贴在这里
and then just paste it down here
我们会把它作为一个私有函数
and we'll keep it as a private function
因为它只被这个函数调用
since it's only called by this function
我们真的不需要暴露这个
and we don't really need to expose this
作为公共职能
as a public function
所以现在我们有一个定义一个打击的模块
so now we have a module that defines one struck
和两个功能
and two functions
幸运的是它仍然有效
and thankfully it still works
我们会看到另一个
we'll see another
即将发布的视频中的结构示例
example of a structure in an upcoming video